

MIKE ANDRIANOV

Ruby / Elixir developer

About me

I have wide experience working on projects of different sizes: from small to large (with more than 100 technical persons). The most important thing for me is a **team**. I strongly believe that achieving the great outcomes is possible only by working in a friendly, respectful, and helpful environment. So if there is a possibility when I can help my team to deliver something even to the detriment of my personal result, I will do it without hesitation.

I always write a **simple**, **readable**, **maintainable code** and follow best practices and pattern design principles. Also, I have experience in **leading projects**. I can do whatever you need: writing technical documentation, making presentations, communicating with clients, interviewing candidates, mentoring others, tasks decomposition, learning a new programming language, or a tool in order to be more useful to the team.

On a daily basis, I use three programming languages: **Ruby**, **Elixir**, and **Javascript**.

Contacts



mike.andr@hey.com



+34 657 081 883



linkedin.com/in/mikeandrianov



Madrid, Spain

Education

University: Belarusian State University

Faculty: Radiophysics and Computer Technologies

Dates Attended: 2010 – 2015

Experience

Software developer at CoverWallet

August 2019 – Present

Description: Multi-tenant application for business commercial insurance

Team structure: 100+ technical specialists

Responsibilities: technical representative of several projects, helping to define roadmap, reviewing tickets for future iterations, new functionality development, bug fixing, mentorship, code reviewing, communication with other departments, customer support, interviewing candidates, writing technical documentation.

Tools: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Elixir, Phoenix, Node.js, ReactJS, Redux, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ

Ruby developer at Oxagile

February 2019 - June 2020

Description: Automated and live proctoring system

Team structure: 20 developers, 7 QAs, 2 business analytics, 3 project managers **Responsibilities**: new functionality development, bug fixing, identifying and clearing technical roadblocks for the team, definition of technical debt management strategy, mentorship, establishment, support and promotion of engineering culture, code reviews, communication with the customer.

Tools: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, ReactJS, Redux, RabbitMQ, WebRTC

Ruby developer at SivinTech

May 2017 - January 2018

Description: Online banking system. Project is a set of microservices

Team structure: 15 developers, 2 QAs, business analytic.

Responsibilities: implementation of the new microservice, code reviews, planning

new functionality for future sprints, fixing bugs for current codebase.

Tools: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Rspec, MySQL

Experience

Ruby developer at ActivePlatform

July 2015 – June 2017

Description: Cloud brokerage platform. The project is a monolith engine-based solution. We used agile methodology, code reviews, TDD.

Team structure: 20 developers, 12 QAs, business analytics, tech writer, etc.

Responsibilities: new functionality development, code reviewing, planning new functionality for future sprints, fixing bugs.

Tools: Ruby on Rails, Grape, Rspec, PostgreSQL, Redis, AngularJS,

Elasticsearch

Ruby developer at Syberry

August 2014 - July 2015

Description: project is CMS for delivering and representation content for **disney.ru** Microservice architecture.

Team structure: 4 - 5 developers, 1 QAs, project manager. **Responsibilities**: new features development, fixing bugs.

Tools: Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Rspec, MongoDB, Redis, BackboneJS, Solr

Ruby developer at Fisikal

April 2012 - Nov 2013

Description: fitness club management software application. Helps trainers and their clients to focus on running their business. Key features: training time booking, payment system, messaging system and so on.

Team structure: 5 developers, 1 QA, customer from UK as a manager.

Responsibilities: new features development, fixing bugs, new functionality planning.

Tools: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, jQuery, Sphinx

Achievements

Have some volunteering experience as lecturer and mentor at summer coding camp called Rubizza (Jul 2017 – Sep 2017). After finishing this camp 20 junior ruby developers have been successfully started their careers.

Posts from my blog (medium.com/@Mike_Andr) were published by Elixir Radar newsletter.